{
    "questions_and_answers": 
    [
       {
         "question": "When was Nitte Mahalinga Adyantaya Memorial Institute of Technology (NMAMIT) established?",
         "answer": "NMAMIT was established in 1986.For more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
       },
       {
         "question": "Is NMAMIT recognized by any regulatory body?",
         "answer": "Yes, NMAMIT is recognized by the All India Council for Technical Education (AICTE), New Delhi. For more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
       },
       {
         "question": "What is NMAMIT's rank in the National Institutional Ranking Framework (NIRF) 2023?",
         "answer": "NMAMIT is ranked in the rank band of 101-150 in NIRF 2023 by the Ministry of Education, Government of India. For more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
       },
       {
         "question": "Which university is NMAMIT affiliated with?",
         "answer": "NMAMIT is a constituent college of Nitte (Deemed to be University), Mangaluru.For more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
       },
       {
         "question": "What are the undergraduate (UG) engineering programs offered by NMAMIT?",
         "answer": "The UG engineering programs offered are: Artificial Intelligence & Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence & Data Science, Biotechnology, Civil Engineering, Computer & Communication Engineering, Computer Science & Engineering, Computer Science (Cyber Security), Computer Science (Full Stack Development), Electrical & Electronics Engineering, Electronics & Communication Engineering, Electronics (VLSI Design & Technology), Electronics & Communication Engineering (ACT), Information Science & Engineering, Mechanical Engineering, and Robotics & Artificial Intelligence.For more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
       },
        {
         "question": "What are the engineering course available for the M.Tech. program at NMAM Institute of Technology (NMAMIT)?",
         "answer": "The seven disciplines for M.Tech. program are Construction Technology, Computer Science & Engineering, Cyber Security, Electric Vehicle Technology, Machine Design, Structural Engineering, and VLSI Design & Embedded Systems.For more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
       },
       {
         "question": "Does NMAMIT have provisions for research work leading to Ph.D.?",
         "answer": "Yes, all the departments at NMAMIT have qualified research guides for students interested in taking up research work leading to Ph.D.For more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
       },
       {
         "question": "What is the total area of NMAMIT's campus?",
         "answer": "NMAMIT's campus is spread over 125 acres.For more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
       },
       {
         "question": "What is the nearest airport to NMAMIT?",
         "answer": "The nearest airport to NMAMIT is Mangaluru International Airport, which is 45 km away.For more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
       },
       {
         "question": "Which are the nearest railway stations to NMAMIT?",
         "answer": "The nearest railway stations to NMAMIT are Udupi (40 km) and Mangaluru (50 km).For more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
       },
       {
         "question": "Which highways are closest to NMAMIT?",
         "answer": "The highways closest to NMAMIT are the ones connecting Karkala and Padubidri, as Nitte is situated between these two towns.For more information, visit https://www.google.co.in/maps/place/N.M.A.M.+Institute+of+Technology/@13.1830012,74.9316861,17.25z/data=!3m1!5s0x3bbcaa27e8fd79af:0x343962e5369a908a!4m6!3m5!1s0x3bbb56415ad85e5b:0x10b77ac6f6afc7fa!8m2!3d13.1830026!4d74.933989!16zL20vMDQxa25k?entry=ttu"
       },
       {
         "question": "Are there any international collaborations for NMAMIT?",
         "answer": "Yes, NMAMIT has active collaborations with several international universities and organizations for faculty and student exchanges, research, internships, and placements.For more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
       },
       {
         "question": "What is the significance of NMAMIT's placement under the 'Platinum' category in AICTE-CII Survey?",
         "answer": "NMAMIT's placement under the 'Platinum' category indicates its high industry linkages, as recognized by the AICTE-CII Survey of Industry-Linked Technical Institutes 2020.For more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
       },
       {
         "question": "What is the significance of NBA accreditation for UG programs at NMAMIT?",
         "answer": "NBA accreditation signifies the quality and standards of the UG programs at NMAMIT, ensuring they meet the set benchmarks.For more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
       },
       {
         "question": "Are there any specific provisions for industry exposure at NMAMIT?",
         "answer": "Yes, NMAMIT has high industry linkages and collaborations, providing students with ample opportunities for industry exposure through internships, projects, and placements.For more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
       },
       {
         "question": "How does NMAMIT promote research among its students?",
         "answer": "NMAMIT promotes research among its students by providing qualified research guides, facilities, and opportunities for collaborative projects.For more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
       },
      {
        "question": "Are there any provisions for co-curricular activities at NMAMIT?",
        "answer": "Yes, NMAMIT encourages co-curricular activities through clubs, societies, and events, fostering holistic development among students.For more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "What measures does NMAMIT take to ensure quality education?",
        "answer": "NMAMIT ensures quality education through experienced faculty, modern infrastructure, industry collaborations, and accreditation processes.For more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "How does NMAMIT support student entrepreneurship?",
        "answer": "NMAMIT supports student entrepreneurship through incubation centers, mentorship programs, and industry tie-ups to nurture innovative ideas and startups.For more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "What distinguishes NMAMIT from other engineering colleges?",
        "answer": "NMAMIT stands out due to its industry linkages, research opportunities, vibrant campus, and emphasis on holistic development.For more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the role of NMAMIT's faculty in fostering student growth?",
        "answer": "NMAMIT's faculty play a crucial role in mentoring, guiding, and inspiring students to excel academically and professionally.For more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "How does NMAMIT ensure student welfare on campus?",
        "answer": "NMAMIT ensures student welfare through counseling services, student support centers, and a conducive learning environment.For more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "How does NMAMIT contribute to regional development?",
        "answer": "NMAMIT contributes to regional development by providing skilled manpower, conducting research, and collaborating with local industries and communities.For more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "What facilities does NMAMIT provide for sports and recreation?",
        "answer": "NMAMIT provides sports facilities, recreational spaces, and organizes events to promote physical fitness and extracurricular activities among students.For more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "How does NMAMIT promote innovation among its students?",
        "answer": "NMAMIT promotes innovation through hackathons, innovation labs, project competitions, and mentorship programs to nurture creativity and problem-solving skills.For more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "What role does NMAMIT play in sustainable development?",
        "answer": "NMAMIT promotes sustainable practices through initiatives such as green campus initiatives, waste management programs, and awareness campaigns.For more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "How does NMAMIT ensure gender diversity on campus?",
        "answer": "NMAMIT encourages gender diversity through awareness programs, scholarships, and inclusive policies to create a supportive environment for all students.For more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "What support does NMAMIT provide for career development?",
        "answer": "NMAMIT offers career counseling, skill development programs, placement assistance, and industry interactions to enhance students' employability.For more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "How does NMAMIT engage with the local community?",
        "answer": "NMAMIT engages with the local community through outreach programs, social initiatives, and collaborative projects to address societal needs and contribute to development.For more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "What initiatives does NMAMIT take for student leadership development?",
        "answer": "NMAMIT offers leadership training, student council activities, and opportunities for participation in clubs and organizations to foster leadership skills among students.For more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "How does NMAMIT ensure academic excellence?",
        "answer": "NMAMIT ensures academic excellence through rigorous curriculum, continuous assessment, faculty development programs, and academic support services.For more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "What are NMAMIT's future plans for growth and development?",
        "answer": "NMAMIT's future plans include expanding infrastructure, enhancing research facilities, strengthening industry collaborations, and promoting innovation and entrepreneurship among students.For more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/about-nmamit-nitte.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is NMAM Institute of Technology's mission and vision?",
        "answer": "NMAM Institute of Technology aims to pursue excellence, empower people, and partner in community development.The mission of NMAM Institute of Technology is to develop as a Center of Excellence by imparting quality education to generate competent, skilled, and humane manpower capable of facing emerging scientific, technological, managerial, and social challenges with credibility, integrity, ethics, and social concern.For more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/vision-mission.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "What are the core values upheld by NMAM Institute of Technology?",
        "answer": "NMAM Institute of Technology values ethics, teamwork, honesty, loyalty, and both professional and personal integrity.For more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/vision-mission.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is NMAM Institute of Technology's quality policy?",
        "answer": "NMAM Institute of Technology recognizes its students, their parents, and prospective employers as esteemed customers. The institute is committed to providing education as per stipulated syllabus using the best practices to achieve customer delight. Its target is to become one of the best technical institutes in India and sustain this position.For more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/vision-mission.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "who is the founder of nitte?",
        "answer": "LATE JUSTICE K. S HEGDE. For more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/founder.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "who is the Principal of NMAMIT and what is his email address?",
        "answer": "Prof. Niranjan N Chiplunkar,his email is principal_nmamit@nitte.edu.in. For more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/principal.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "who is the Vice principal & Dean of NMAMIT and what is his email address?",
        "answer": "Dr. I. Ramesh Mithanthaya, his email is viceprincipal.nmamit@nitte.edu.in. For more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/vice-principal.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "who is the Vice Principal & Controller of Examinations of NMAMIT?",
        "answer": "Dr. Shrinivasa Rao B.R.For more information, visit https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/vice-principal.php"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the email address of the Dean (Admissions) at NMAM Institute of Technology?",
        "answer": "The email address of the Dean (Admissions) at NMAM Institute of Technology is krshetty@nitte.edu.in. For further details refer: https://nmamit.nitte.edu.in/contact-nmamit.php"
      }
   ]
}
